Lee Payne

website: https://www.lap-it.com

Email: lee@lap-it.com, LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/lapayne1982



Profile

An experienced, focused, determined, and enthusiastic IT leader with a proven history across the entire technology stack in both technical implementation and managerial roles.

Professional bodies

- Chartered member of the Chartered Management Institute
- Member of the Association of MBA's

Career History

July 2019 – Present, Computershare Position: Web Environments Manager/DevOps Manager

- Managing a team of 9 engineers across 4 sites within Europe,
- Implementing Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) and DevOps ideas,
- Capacity management, CAPEX & OPEX planning
- Mentoring, performance management, appraisal, and development plans for the team.
- Reduced the average age of tickets by 22 days to 4 days,
- Reduced the volume of tickets into the team by 56%
- Reduced out of hours callouts by 90%,
- Reduced OPEX by reducing tooling in use.
- Embedded operational support for M365 into existing team structures.
- Implementing chatbot functionality to the service desk

March 2018 – July 2019, Computershare Position: Server, Storage, Data Centre, and Open Systems Manager

- Responsible for 13 engineers across 2 sites in the UK,
- Managing the CAPEX and OPEX requirements for the data centres, servers and infrastructure software products (exchange, active directory etc..).
- Managed a portfolio of CSI projects to fix long outstanding issues
- Reduced the support ticket backlog by 70%,
- Merged two disparate teams into one with no turnover of staff,
- Reduced security vulnerabilities by 80%,
- Introduced the usage of cloud services to enable faster response in the event of DR.

March 2016-March 2018, Computershare Position: Network & Voice Manager

- Expanded the team from 2 to 8 engineers across 2 sites,
- Transitioned some tasks to the service desk to reduce cost,
- Introduced a skills matrix and development plans to reduce skills gaps
- Managed the CAPEX & OPEX budget for the team
- Oversaw a large switch replacement programme across multiple sites throughout EMEA.

July 2013-March 2016, Computershare

Position: Network Engineer

2006 – June 2013, Computershare Position: Server Support Engineer

2004 – 2006, Kennet and North Wiltshire PCT Position: Desktop/Server Support Engineer

Formal Education

- MBA Technology Management (pass). The Open University, 2014-2018
- Level 5 Diploma in Leadership & Management (pass), Chartered Management Institute, 2014
- Certificate in Business Administration (pass), Swindon College, 2005
- BSc (Hons) Computer Science (2:1), University of the West of England, 2000-2004

Professional Qualifications

- CMI Chartered Manager
- ITIL 4 Managing Professional
- ITIL 4 Strategic Leader
- PRINCE2 Practitioner
- Microsoft Certified AI Engineer Associate
- Microsoft Certified Azure Solutions Architect Expert
- Microsoft Certified DevOps Expert
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Security Engineer Associate
- Microsoft Certified Azure Administrator
- Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator Server 2016 (MCSA Server 2016)
- Microsoft Certified Systems Expert: Cloud Platform and infrastructure (MCSE 2016)

Technologies & Tools

| OS & Cloud | Infrastructure | DevOps |
|----------------|-------------------------|-------------------|
| Windows server | SCOM | Azure DevOp's |
| Linux | SCCM | Octopus deploy |
| Azure | vSphere/ESX | Jenkins |
| AWS | Enterprise Vault | Docker/Kubernetes |
| | F5 Big-IP | Puppet |

Hobbies and Interests

I am a keen PADI qualified Scuba Diver having dived in Australia and Turkey, I enjoy hiking, trying new restaurants and cuisines, reading both technical and non-technical books as well as spending as much time with my family that I can.